# Nandhini Nagarajan

nandhininagarajan98@gmail.com

74189 65367

Barani Nilaya, Door No:28,4th Main Road, Vinayaka Layout Bangalore,

Karnataka



# **Summary**

Strongly dedicated and resourceful Talent Acquisition Specialist and Executive Recruiter for 4+ years of Experience with an excellent record of identifying and placing superior job candidates. Adept at networking with a variety of in-person and online personnel sources. Able to functionsuperbly with little to no supervision or as part of a hiring team. Talent recruitment and acquisition professional with experience developing and executing recruiting plans within both internal and external settings. Manage all phases of full-cycle recruiting.

#### **Experience**

# **Executive Recruitment**

Sacha Engineering Solutions (RLE)-Bengaluru, KA Worked for FORD MOTOR Company

01/2023-Present

- Participated in recruitment, interview and selection of candidates for various levels of position openings in IT and Non- IT Requirement
- Sourced, screened, evaluated and selected candidates through a structured recruitment process designed to obtain the best candidate.
- Informed applicants of job duties and responsibilities, compensation and benefits, work schedules and working conditions, company policies, promotional opportunities, and other related information.
- Generated qualified candidates through cost-effective efforts (i.e., alternative sourcing).
- Utilized a resume database for sourcing and tracking of all candidates.
- Sourcing through various Job portals such as Naukri, Monster and Very good in LinkedIn
- Identified, convinced and motivated the potential candidates.
- Ensured accurate and timely delivery of the resume.
- Coordinated with the Client's panel members to Schedule Interviews.
- Recruited for Middle & Senior level positions.
- Got requirements & analyzed the skill sets of the requirements.
- Take care of End-to-End recruitment process starting from screening to Releasing the offer

Domain Handled: Embedded / Model Based Development / Validation and Verification/ADAS/ Autosar /SysML/Modelling profiles

# Internal Recruiter and Senior Business Development Associate Think and Learn Pvt. Ltd (BYJUS) • Chennai, Tamil Nadu

11/2020 - 02/2022

- Responsible for Lead Generation, Targeting, Prospecting, Negotiating and Closing. Almost with 1.5 years if experience in recruiting the candidates for Ed-tech based companies. Completely taking care of sourcing the profiles, screening them and preparing for interviews and releasing the offer.
- · Driving and managing the entire sales process from targeting and prospecting to closing the sale.
- Assist with proactive outreach efforts and campaigns to build relationships and identify opportunities with prospective clients.
- · Lead and grow our Business Development team to acquire new institutional/educational clients in the specifiedregion/market.
- Performed activities related to Business Development through visiting school, to tie-up and coordinating seminars at school for promoting the products.
- Managing sales for K-12 (4th- 12th), CAT, GMAT in B2B/B2C sales segment in Tamil Nadu and Bangalore. Driving and managing the entire sales process from targeting and prospecting to closing the sale.
- Manage day-to-day operational duties (manage and track sales lead flow, manage and maintain CRM database, report, weekly activities and accomplishment.
- Desktop procedures with the Client Onboarding and Quality Control teams and drive global consistency as they are implemented to meet new and enhanced standards.
- Work with senior business development colleagues and investment teams to develop a compelling sales strategyfor each opportunity. Handled both Lead square portal and ATS for recruiting purposes.
- Hands-on experience in B2B and B2C sales along with providing technical support in onboarding the clients at thewebsite. Generated almost more than 30Lakhs of revenue within my first 6 months' period.

Domain Handled: Ed-Tech / Freshers / Business development/ Marketing

### **Talent Acquisition Specialist/Recruiter**

# VIVA USA Inc • Chennai, Tamil Nadu (01/2019-05/2019 - Internship)

06/2019 - 11/2020

- Creates and maintains a close and healthy working relationship as the liaison between HR and the Service Managers Assist with candidate tracking across various recruitment/HRIS platforms.
- · Target and acquire unique talent that fills a certain niche within a boutique management consulting firm. Managed
- · companywide sourcing campaigns through networking events, social media, job boards, and University career fairs.
- Managed the candidate experience by being the initial contact, moving candidates through the interviewing process, prescreening, and maintaining the recruitment pipeline.
- Excellent interpersonal and superior verbal & written communication skills.
- Able to communicate with internal and external business partners. Used sourcing website like Naukri, Monster, Indeed and Career Builder for internal recruiting, Also involved in Bulk Hiring
- Identifies potential internal applicants, processes applications from internal applicants and works with Managers to place/promote from within Company
- · Provides assistance in monitoring employee performance appraisal process. Working
- · knowledge of employment law and industry best practices.
- Working experience with fortune 500 clients such as Siemens, Johndeere, Caterpillar, Motorola, Amazon, Google, Baxter, Abbott, AbbVie, GeneralElectric (GE), and state clients.
- Recruiting qualified candidates for Engineering, Pharmaceutical, Medical manufacturer and various manufacturing clients. Strong
  experience and Proficiency in using ATS (Applicant Tracking Systems). Sourced, pre-screened and recruited candidates for
  various contract and contract to hire positions. Submitted qualified profiles for Validation, Quality, Design, Embedded, EU
  MDR, HF, Mech. and Elect. Engineer roles.

**Domain Handled**: Non-IT: Embedded / Manufacturing/ Validation and Verification / ADAS / Matlab/C developer/Java Developer/Mainframe/ Dot net developer/QA automation and Manual

#### **Skills**

Recruiting, Sourcing, On Boarding, IT Recruitment, Human Resource, Business Intelligence, ATS Tool, CRM Tool, Business Development, Client Relationship, Time Management, Lead Generation, Communication skill, Boolean Search, Lead square portal

Languages: C++, Java, MySQL and Python

# **Education:**

Bachelors of Engineering (Electronics and Communication)
Saranathan College of Engineering (ANNA UNIVERSITY)

Graduated with 9.34 CGPA

# **Academic Projects**

**Image Compression using Predictive Method:** Image can be compressed using the predictive image compression algorithm using predictive coding. Prediction scheme generates an image map which indicates the prediction errors. Next skipping into ANFIS, which has reduced the dimensionality of the problem which reduces the computation required during speech. Finally it will display the outputs such as on the output screen MSE, PSNR and compression ratio.

**Cell phone Controlled Robot:** The basic idea of the project is to make the robot controlled using a mobile phone and without using the micro controller.